Hello English learners, welcome
back to English, Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Catherine, and today
we're talking about something very serious.
Very serious.
Today we're talking
about capital punishment.
So if you've never
heard that phrase before,
you might have heard another name for
this topic is called "The Death Penalty.
" Right.
So if you commit a crime,
and basically the judge says
that you will have to be
put to death for that crime.
All right, so many countries
no longer have this, this law.
The United States, you can see it in some
places, some states, but not in others.
So what we're talking
about today is the
debate between to have the
death penalty and to not have it.
All right.
So we're going to
actually have a little
debate in the end of if we agree that
we should have the death penalty or not.
But before that, why don't we listen
to this dialogue for the first time?
For example, we could
bring back the death
penalty for murder, give
longer prison sentences
for lesser offenses, and
lock up juvenile offenders.
It would sound like
really draconian measures.
Firstly, what do you do
about miscarriages of
justice if you've already put
innocent people to death?
You'd only use capital
punishment if you're
absolutely sure that you'd
convicted the right person.
But there have been
many cases of wrongful
conviction where people have
been imprisoned for many years.
The authorities were
sure at the time, but later
it was shown that the
evidence was unreliable.
In some cases, it had been
fabricated by the police.
Well, no system of
justice can be perfect, but
surely there's a good case for longer
prison sentences to deter serious crime.
I doubt whether they
could act as an effective
deterrent while the
detection rate is so low.
The best way to prevent
crime is to convince
people who commit it that
they're going to be caught.
It doesn't make sense to divert all
your resources into the prison system.
But if you detect more crime,
you still still need prisons.
In my reckoning, if
we could lock up more
juvenile criminals, they'd learn
that they can't get away with it.
Soft sentences will merely
encourage them to do it again.
Yes, but remember that prisons
are often schools for criminals.
To remove crime from society,
you really have to tackle its causes.
Well, if I were president, I would
impose tougher laws and punishment.
I would have a peaceful
society based on fear
of punishment, not consciousness
of doing the right thing.
Do sound like a dictator.
Well, if it works, why not?
All right, so Marco,
there's a lot of really
great legal terms here,
legal and crime terms.
And so let's look at a few of
these in today's language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so let's take
a look at the first one.
They mentioned juvenile offenders.
All right, so let's look
at these two words,
because, well, a fender
can be pretty general.
It's someone who commits a crime.
So an offender, but we're talking
about a special kind of offender here.
We're talking about juvenile offenders.
So they're young offenders, right?
And in America, legally, you're a juvenile
offender if you're under the age of 18.
Okay, so if you commit
a crime while you are
a juvenile, you get
judged differently, right?
You don't get the same
treatment as an adult, right?
But usually the
punishments are not as harsh,
because people like
to think that younger
people, younger children or teenagers,
they don't really understand the law.
They don't really understand crime or good
and bad, so it should be easier on them.
Mm-hmm.
All right, very good.
So we have juvenile offenders, and
we also have wrongful conviction.
All right, this is an uh
oh moment for a judge,
because a wrongful conviction, well,
conviction first of all is a decision.
So this is a court's
decision on whether or not
a person is guilty, so
you convicted the person.
Right, Marco was convicted
guilty of stealing my computer.
I was too.
That happened.
Right.
But uh, it's a wrongful
conviction if Marco
didn't really steal a computer,
but we decided that he did.
Okay.
So it was a wrong decision.
Right, it was a bad
decision in the sense that
it's actually not what
happened in reality.
Mm-hmm.
A wrongful conviction, very good.
And actually related
to a wrongful conviction,
many times it happens because
evidence is fabricated by the police.
All right.
So this is a big no-no.
This is something that
really shouldn't happen,
and it's against the
law in many countries.
So fabrication or to fabricate is
to fake, to make something up.
And so evidence that's fabricated is evidence
that the police or other people create
to try and make someone look
guilty, but it's not actually evidence.
It's not really.
It's not true.
Right.
And now moving on, they were
talking about a deterrent for crime.
Okay.
So to deter a verb, to deter means to
try and get someone to not do something.
All right.
So I'm going to try and deter my
staff from taking early lunch breaks.
So I'm going to punish
someone as a deterrent.
As a deterrent.
You have the verb deter and
you have the noun a deterrent.
Right.
Yeah.
And so oftentimes very strict
laws are meant to be deterrence.
They're meant to keep people from
doing bad things, from breaking the law.
All right.
So for example, capital punishment
is one of those deterrence.
If you kill somebody, then if you get
caught, you are also going to be killed.
So I mean, I'm never going
to kill anyone because I don't
want the law to decide
that I'm going to get killed.
Exactly.
But for today, they were talking
about imposing tougher laws.
I would impose tougher laws.
Okay.
So to impose is a verb that means
to put in place or to set up or enact.
And so by force, right, you don't
really, you don't really agree to do it.
Like the dictator imposes his will.
All right.
So he makes everyone do what he wants, but
we can impose measures that do something.
Yeah.
It's kind of like
forcibly making people
follow some kind of
rule or follow a person.
Now sometimes you
would see that you have a
company or you have
people at your house and
they're like, well, you
know, stay over for
dinner and they're like, oh,
I wouldn't want to impose.
All right.
So I wouldn't want to
bother you or I wouldn't
want to create more
work for you because
you know, when you're
making food, you have all
these people, they don't
want to impose on you.
All right.
So that's another way of
using this impose on somebody.
All right.
So after all of these words
that we've taken a look
at, why don't we start
now with fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
Okay.
So as you know,
fluency builder is a place
where you get to talk
about some phrases and
words that allow you to
be more fluent in English.
So these are sometimes idioms or sometimes
phrases, words that go together commonly.
And the first one is no exception.
It's a miscarriage.
So miscarriage of justice.
All right.
A miscarriage of justice.
Now we have different words here.
The first one, miscarriage, it's
usually related to a medical term.
Right.
It's a pregnancy that has a sad result.
It's a pregnancy where the woman's
baby dies or the woman loses the baby.
And a miscarriage of justice is a metaphor.
It's a way to say that
justice was not carried out.
It means that, for example,
with those wrongful
convictions, the law failed
to accomplish its objective.
And to accomplish its
objective and to be fair.
Okay.
So a miscarriage of justice, interesting.
And moving on to our
next phrase, they were
talking and discussing this
whole death penalty situation.
And she mentioned in my reckoning.
All right.
So this is a great way to share your
opinion or your idea with someone.
You're saying pretty
much, in my opinion,
according to me or, you know,
the way I'm thinking is this.
So I can also say I reckon, right?
Exactly.
I reckon it's going to rain later.
I think it's going to rain.
So in my reckoning, in my opinion.
All right.
I reckon.
And to finish off
fluency builder, they said
that the person or the criminal
couldn't get away with it.
All right.
So this is another one
of those phrases that
each word maybe means
something different.
You can get somewhere,
but put together to
get away with something
means to do something
bad or illegal or that's
not OK without getting
caught or being punished
or being punished.
So you can say, get away with murder.
You know, he got away with murder.
You know, he did something that was
really, really bad, but no one caught him.
And also it means the criminal
got away so they couldn't catch him.
Right.
Or I could always say
to my brother, he would
always lie to my parents
and get away with it.
So he never got caught.
He never got punished.
OK, so he got away
with his lie or got away.
His way.
All right.
So I think this is an interesting phrase.
Why don't we listen to a
couple of more examples.
Example one.
Do you think we could get away
with using the cheaper product?
Example two.
Thieves got away with two
Picasso's which were never found.
Example three.
He almost got away with murder.
Unfortunately for him, the
police discovered his secret.
So we've taken a look
at a lot of great phrases.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for
the last time and then we'll come back.
What's all for today's class?
Do you think we should be tougher on crime?
Well, it depends on what you mean.
For example, we could
bring back the death
penalty for murder, give
longer prison sentences
for lesser offenses, and
lock up juvenile offenders.
It would sound like
really draconian measures.
What do you do about
miscarriages of justice
if you've already put
innocent people to death?
You'd only use capital
punishment if you're
absolutely sure that you'd
convicted the right person.
But there have been
many cases of wrongful
conviction where people have
been imprisoned for many years.
The authorities were
sure at the time, but later
it was shown that the
evidence was unreliable.
In some cases, it had been
fabricated by the police.
Well, no system of
justice can be perfect, but
surely there's a good case for longer
prison sentences to deter serious crime.
I doubt whether they
could act as an effective
deterrent while the
detection rate is so low.
The best way to prevent
crime is to convince
people who commit it that
they're going to be caught.
It doesn't make sense to divert all
your resources into the prison system.
But if you detect more
crimes, you'll still need prisons.
In my reckoning, if
we could lock up more
juvenile criminals, they'd learn
that they can't get away with it.
Sentences will merely
encourage them to do it again.
Yes, but remember that prisons
are often schools for criminals.
To remove crime from society,
you really have to tackle its causes.
Well, if I were president, I would
impose tougher laws and punishment.
I would have a peaceful
society based on fear
of punishment, not consciousness
of doing the right thing.
You sound like a dictator.
Well, if it works, why not?
All right, so now the big question, Catherine,
do you agree with the death penalty?
Oh, this is a big one, and I don't
think we have enough time to go into it.
In much detail here, but I
definitely think that is extreme, right?
And so we have this
phrase, draconian measures.
Right, they mentioned that in dialogue.
Yeah, so draconian, something that's
draconian is excessive or severe, you know?
And I think that there
are a lot of reasons
not to have the death
penalty because the death
penalty, well, you're pretty much saying
we as a society think that murder is wrong,
but we're going to show
you that you've done
a wrong thing, like a bad thing
that's against the law by killing you.
Mm hmm.
All right, and so I have
to disagree with that on
a philosophical level,
but what about practical?
Practically speaking,
I think that there
are a lot of problems
with the prison system
and the legal system
in the United States, for
example, because
prisons are really crowded.
One percent of the American
population is imprisoned.
And so I think that so long as the prison
system still has problems, there's a really
good argument for having the death penalty,
but still, I think that it's excessive and
it's unnecessary and that there are
other ways to treat and punish prisoners.
It is an interesting topic
because you have many different
angles that are in favor or
against the death penalty.
For example, you have religious views where
you say that you should not take a life of
another person no matter what, or you have
other views that say that the death penalty
is simply wrong and that you can't
write a wrong with another wrong.
Right.
Exactly.
So it kind of doesn't make sense.
But at the same time, you do, like you say,
the prisons are full of people and it costs
around, I think it's $12,000 a year
per person to keep them in prison.
So what do you do with
all of these people that
have life sentences that are going
to spend the rest of their lives in jail?
So it is interesting.
And many countries
are very, very strict with
their legal system in comparison
with the United States, right?
Definitely.
But there is a statistic
that's pretty stunning
that I think among
the top 20 developed
nations in the world,
I think only the United
States is the one
with the death penalty.
Exactly.
And actually, the ratio
of the people compared
to the population
that are in jail is much
higher in the United States
than in other countries.
That's true.
So it is a very questionable topic,
but we want to know what you think.
Do you think that the death penalty
is a justifiable way to do justice?
Or do you think maybe it's just wrong
and we shouldn't have it anymore?
Yeah, we're hoping that this will get
the conversation going on our website.
If you have any opinions,
please let us know about them.
EnglishPod.com is the website.
And of course, you can always email us
or send us a PM if you're a little bit shy.
All right.
So we'll see you guys there.
Bye, everyone.
Bye.